<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COMP 426 on Modern Web Programming</title>
    <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content in COMP 426 on Modern Web Programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;span xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; xmlns:dct=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/terms/&#34;&gt;&lt;a property=&#34;dct:title&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34; href=&#34;https://comp426.johndmart.in&#34;&gt;COMP 426: Modern Web Programming&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; {year} by &lt;a rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL dct:creator&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; href=&#34;https://johndmart.in&#34;&gt;John D. Martin III&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/?ref=chooser-v1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;license noopener noreferrer&#34; style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;img style=&#34;height:13px!important;margin-left:3px;vertical-align:text-bottom;&#34; src=&#34;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/cc.svg?ref=chooser-v1&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;height:13px!important;margin-left:3px;vertical-align:text-bottom;&#34; src=&#34;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/by.svg?ref=chooser-v1&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;height:13px!important;margin-left:3px;vertical-align:text-bottom;&#34; src=&#34;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/nc.svg?ref=chooser-v1&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;height:13px!important;margin-left:3px;vertical-align:text-bottom;&#34; src=&#34;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/sa.svg?ref=chooser-v1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 04:15:05 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://comp426.johndmart.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>git</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/scm/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/scm/</guid>
        <description>git is a distributed version control system that keeps track of the changes between plaintext source files. It can be used for collaboration or for managing and keeping track of workflows for individuals. While primarily intended for software source code, git works with any plaintext files, and so can also be used for authoring of other kinds.
git basics git official documentation
You should become conversant with the official documentation for git.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GitHub</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hub/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:41:37 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hub/</guid>
        <description>GitHub is a platform that allows for users to keep copies of their open source, plaintext repositories online, in a single centralized location. It also adds a social interaction layer to the process of managing version-controlled source files.
GitHub Basics Hello World - GitHub Guides
Keeping GitHub forks up to date with upstream source Keeping your forked repo synced with the upstream source - Nitin Venkatesh
Syncing a fork - GitHub Help</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GitHub Actions</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hubactions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:42:12 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hubactions/</guid>
        <description>GitHub Actions allows for testing, compiling, and other workflow tasks to be performed on GitHub after you push to a repository housed there. COMP 426 uses these for autograding and other basic evaluation of assignments when you submit them. It is useful to become familiar with how it works so that you can monitor your autograded assignments when you submit them.
GitHub Actions - GitHub Docs</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GitHub Classroom</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hubclassroom/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:42:18 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hubclassroom/</guid>
        <description>GitHub Classroom allows your instructors to distribute starter code for assignments, automatically create and manage repositories for student work, and automatically grade work sumbitted by push to GitHub. This is how all assignments will be managed for COMP426.
You can install an extension in VSCode that will let you simplify the process of accepting and submitting assignments.
Install GitHub Classroom extension on VSCode</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>mod01 HTML &#43; CSS Crash Course</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod01/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod01/</guid>
        <description>HTML and CSS The first real assignment is meant to get you comfortable with the basics of HTML and CSS. Whether you know it very well already or if you need a refresher, going through this module and then a01 should put you in a good position to continue through the rest of the assignments.
Knowing these markup languages is very important for being a good web developer. Both HTML and CSS are straightforward and well-documented.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>tl;dr</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/tldr/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/tldr/</guid>
        <description>What is it? This is a class about building things that make the web go. We&amp;rsquo;re going to learn how to do that by doing that.
What are we doing? This semester we are going to focus on systems for collecting and managing public health information because we are in an ongoing public health crisis and that seems really relevant.
COVID-19 is still a thing We&amp;rsquo;re going to be doing Zoom class for the first few weeks until we see how things are going around campus with COVID-19.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Course objectives</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/objectives/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/objectives/</guid>
        <description>Technical skills Working through this course facliltates students to exercise a range of skils:
 Design and build RESTful API endpoints for access to a server-side information source (database, third-party API, etc.) Design objects using the JavaScript prototype-based object model Employ functional programming techniques implemented in JavaScript for asynchronous event-handling Use asynchronous techniques to implement client-server interactions with a RESTful API Manipulate the Document Oject Model (DOM) using a variety of techniques for presenting information client-side Construct client-side/browesr-based interactive applications/interfaces Use CSS and HTML for basic aesthetics in interface design  Planning and management skills In addition to the above, students will be able to:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Course structure</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/structure/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/structure/</guid>
        <description>Class sessions We will combine demonstrations and lectures with hand-on work in class. Some class time will be reserved for you to work with your teams.
Remote availability Class sessions are all going to be available to stream live on Zoom. This is intended to help manage dealing with the uncertainty of conditions this semester.
Session recordings Sessions will all be recorded and archived in Panopto so that you can access them later.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>mod03 JavaScript Functions</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod03/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod03/</guid>
        <description>In a03, we&amp;rsquo;re writing some basic JS functions that can be called to return values outside of a web browser. This module includes some information and links about JS functions and a walkthrough of creating a very basic set. Some of this is covered in the a03 instructions as well. You can use this as a reference to expand on the information presented in the instructions.
How do functions work in JavaScript?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Deliverables and assessments</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/assignments/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/assignments/</guid>
        <description>Assignments This is a tentative list of assignments. These may be adjusted or merged depending on how the course flows.
   Assignment Title Topics covered     a00 Setup Installing software; git and Github; bash/command line   a01 Node Package management; creating packages; Node.js; npm   a02 Functions Running JavaScript as program; JavaScript functions   a03 API Turning functions into endpoints; REST; Express   a04 Get Getting information from an API in a web interface; Next.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Evaluation</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/evaluation/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/evaluation/</guid>
        <description>Grade breakdown Grading will be based on 1,000,000 points. The breakdown is as follows.
   Component Description Quantity Points Subtotal     Assignments Individual programmind assignments 10 50,000 500,000   Final project Team-based app development 1 300,000 300,000   Assessments Questionnaires 3 50,000 150,000   Engagement GitHub commits 100 500 50,000   Total    1,000,000    Components Assignments Each of the individual programmin assignments will be worth 50,000 points and will be automatically evaluated.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Honor Code</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/honor/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/honor/</guid>
        <description>The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill has had a student-led honor system for over 100 years. Academic integrity is at the heart of Carolina and we all are responsible for upholding the ideals of honor and integrity. The student-led Honor System is responsible for adjudicating any suspected violations of the Honor Code and all suspected instances of academic dishonesty will be reported to the Honor System. Information, including your responsibilities as a student, is outlined in the Instrument of Student Judicial Governance.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mental health and well-being</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/wellbeing/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/wellbeing/</guid>
        <description>Counseling and Psychological Services (CAPS) CAPS is strongly committed to addressing the mental health needs of a diverse student body throughtimely access to consultation and connection to clinically appropriate services, whether for short or long-term needs.
Go to their website: https://caps.unc.edu/ or visit their facilities on the third floor of the Campus Health Services building for a walk-in evaluation to learn more.
Help us help you If you are struggling, speak to a TA and/or the instructor.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Accessibility</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/accessibility/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/accessibility/</guid>
        <description>Accessibility Resources The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill facilitates the implementation of reasonable accommodations, including resources and services, for students with disabilities, chronic medical conditions, a temporary disability or pregnancy complications resulting in barriers to fully accessing University courses, programs and activities.
Accommodations are determined through the Office of Accessibility. Resources and Service (ARS) for individuals with documented qualifying disabilities in accordance with applicable state and federal laws. See the ARS Website for contact information: https://ars.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Title IX</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/title9/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/title9/</guid>
        <description>Title IX Resources Any student who is impacted by discrimination, harassment, interpersonal (relationship) violence, sexual violence, sexual exploitation, or stalking is encouraged to seek resources on campus or in the community.
Please contact the Director of Title IX Compliance (Adrienne Allison – Adrienne.allison@unc.edu), Report and Response Coordinators in the Equal Opportunity and Compliance Office (reportandresponse@unc.edu), Counseling and Psychological Services (confidential), or the Gender Violence Services Coordinators (gvsc@unc.edu; confidential) to discuss your specific needs.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Disclaimer</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/disclaimer/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/disclaimer/</guid>
        <description>The instructor reserves to right to make changes to the syllabus, including any project due dates, assessment dates, assignments, or other aspects of the schedule and structure.
Things change. We live in uncertain times. We will adjust the course accordingly if it becomes necessary to do so.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mod05</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod05/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 12:53:01 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod05/</guid>
        <description></description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>JS Functions</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/javascript/functions/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/javascript/functions/</guid>
        <description>JavaScript Functions - w3schools
Functions - JavaScript - Mozilla Developer Network
Differences Between var and let - JavaScript Tutorials</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>mod04 REST, CRUD, and databases</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod04/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod04/</guid>
        <description>Application Programming Interface (API) An API is the interface layer between two pieces of software that don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily speak the same langauge. The function of an API is to translate from one platform/piece of software to another.
An API call is a process through which requests are made and data is retrieved from an API by a client. It looks something like this:
 A client makes a request for some data.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Node</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/javascript/node/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/javascript/node/</guid>
        <description>Node.js v16.10.0 documentation
ECMAScript Modules (ESM) ECMAScript Modules (ESM) documentation
Using ECMAScript modules (ESM) with Node.js - Diogo Souza</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Setup for Mac OSX</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/software/mac/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/software/mac/</guid>
        <description>To be a successful web developer in COMP 426, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install some software on your computer. Follow the guide on this page if you have a Mac running OSX.
Chrome Web Browser Your projects in this course will run in a web browser. While most web browsers should work, we only support and test in the Google Chrome web browser. Install it by following the instructions below. We suggest making it your computer&amp;rsquo;s default web browser.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software setup for Windows</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/software/windows/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/software/windows/</guid>
        <description>To be a successful web developer in COMP 426, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install some software on your computer. Follow the guide on this page if you have a Windows computer.
Chrome Web Browser Your projects in this course will run in a web browser. While most web browsers should work, we only support and test in the Google Chrome web browser. Install it by following the instructions below. We suggest making it your computer&amp;rsquo;s default web browser.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Validators</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/validators/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/validators/</guid>
        <description>Here are some links to validators that you can use to check your assignment code. We will run all your code through a validator as part of your assignment submission. You should too.
Validators will tell you exactly what you need to know to fix the errors in your code.
HTML, CSS, etc. W3C Markup Validation Service (HTML)
W3C has a bunch of different validators that can check CSS, web platforms (mobile ready), dead links, RSS, and one that checks all of these things.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>