<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COMP 426 on Modern Web Programming</title>
    <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content in COMP 426 on Modern Web Programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;span xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; xmlns:dct=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/terms/&#34;&gt;&lt;a property=&#34;dct:title&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34; href=&#34;https://comp426.johndmart.in&#34;&gt;COMP 426: Modern Web Programming&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; {year} by &lt;a rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL dct:creator&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; href=&#34;https://johndmart.in&#34;&gt;John D. Martin III&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/?ref=chooser-v1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;license noopener noreferrer&#34; style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;img style=&#34;height:13px!important;margin-left:3px;vertical-align:text-bottom;&#34; src=&#34;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/cc.svg?ref=chooser-v1&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;height:13px!important;margin-left:3px;vertical-align:text-bottom;&#34; src=&#34;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/by.svg?ref=chooser-v1&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;height:13px!important;margin-left:3px;vertical-align:text-bottom;&#34; src=&#34;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/nc.svg?ref=chooser-v1&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;height:13px!important;margin-left:3px;vertical-align:text-bottom;&#34; src=&#34;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/sa.svg?ref=chooser-v1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 04:15:05 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://comp426.johndmart.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>git</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/scm/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/scm/</guid>
        <description>git is a distributed version control system that keeps track of the changes between plaintext source files. It can be used for collaboration or for managing and keeping track of workflows for individuals. While primarily intended for software source code, git works with any plaintext files, and so can also be used for authoring of other kinds.
git basics git official documentation
You should become conversant with the official documentation for git.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GitHub</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hub/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:41:37 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hub/</guid>
        <description>GitHub is a platform that allows for users to keep copies of their open source, plaintext repositories online, in a single centralized location. It also adds a social interaction layer to the process of managing version-controlled source files.
GitHub Basics Hello World - GitHub Guides
Keeping GitHub forks up to date with upstream source Keeping your forked repo synced with the upstream source - Nitin Venkatesh
Syncing a fork - GitHub Help</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GitHub Actions</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hubactions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:42:12 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hubactions/</guid>
        <description>GitHub Actions allows for testing, compiling, and other workflow tasks to be performed on GitHub after you push to a repository housed there. COMP 426 uses these for autograding and other basic evaluation of assignments when you submit them. It is useful to become familiar with how it works so that you can monitor your autograded assignments when you submit them.
GitHub Actions - GitHub Docs</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GitHub Classroom</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hubclassroom/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:42:18 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hubclassroom/</guid>
        <description>GitHub Classroom allows your instructors to distribute starter code for assignments, automatically create and manage repositories for student work, and automatically grade work sumbitted by push to GitHub. This is how all assignments will be managed for COMP426.
You can install an extension in VSCode that will let you simplify the process of accepting and submitting assignments.
Install GitHub Classroom extension on VSCode</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>mod01 HTML &#43; CSS Crash Course</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod01/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod01/</guid>
        <description>HTML and CSS The first real assignment is meant to get you comfortable with the basics of HTML and CSS. Whether you know it very well already or if you need a refresher, going through this module and then a01 should put you in a good position to continue through the rest of the assignments.
Knowing these markup languages is very important for being a good web developer. Both HTML and CSS are straightforward and well-documented.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>tl;dr</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/tldr/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/syllabus/tldr/</guid>
        <description>What is it? This is a class about building things that make the web go. We&amp;rsquo;re going to learn how to do that by doing that.
What are we doing? This semester we are going to focus on systems for collecting and managing public health information because we are in an ongoing public health crisis and that seems really relevant.
COVID-19 is still a thing We&amp;rsquo;re going to be doing Zoom class for the first few weeks until we see how things are going around campus with COVID-19.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>mod03 JavaScript Functions</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod03/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod03/</guid>
        <description>In a03, we&amp;rsquo;re writing some basic JS functions that can be called to return values outside of a web browser. This module includes some information and links about JS functions and a walkthrough of creating a very basic set. Some of this is covered in the a03 instructions as well. You can use this as a reference to expand on the information presented in the instructions.
How do functions work in JavaScript?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mod05</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod05/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 12:53:01 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod05/</guid>
        <description></description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>JS Functions</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/javascript/functions/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/javascript/functions/</guid>
        <description>JavaScript Functions - w3schools
Functions - JavaScript - Mozilla Developer Network
Differences Between var and let - JavaScript Tutorials</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>mod04 REST, CRUD, and databases</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod04/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod04/</guid>
        <description>Application Programming Interface (API) An API is the interface layer between two pieces of software that don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily speak the same langauge. The function of an API is to translate from one platform/piece of software to another.
An API call is a process through which requests are made and data is retrieved from an API by a client. It looks something like this:
 A client makes a request for some data.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Node</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/javascript/node/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/javascript/node/</guid>
        <description>Node.js v16.10.0 documentation
ECMAScript Modules (ESM) ECMAScript Modules (ESM) documentation
Using ECMAScript modules (ESM) with Node.js - Diogo Souza</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Setup for Mac OSX</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/software/mac/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/software/mac/</guid>
        <description>To be a successful web developer in COMP 426, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install some software on your computer. Follow the guide on this page if you have a Mac running OSX.
Chrome Web Browser Your projects in this course will run in a web browser. While most web browsers should work, we only support and test in the Google Chrome web browser. Install it by following the instructions below. We suggest making it your computer&amp;rsquo;s default web browser.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software setup for Windows</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/software/windows/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/software/windows/</guid>
        <description>To be a successful web developer in COMP 426, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install some software on your computer. Follow the guide on this page if you have a Windows computer.
Chrome Web Browser Your projects in this course will run in a web browser. While most web browsers should work, we only support and test in the Google Chrome web browser. Install it by following the instructions below. We suggest making it your computer&amp;rsquo;s default web browser.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Validators</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/validators/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/validators/</guid>
        <description>Here are some links to validators that you can use to check your assignment code. We will run all your code through a validator as part of your assignment submission. You should too.
Validators will tell you exactly what you need to know to fix the errors in your code.
HTML, CSS, etc. W3C Markup Validation Service (HTML)
W3C has a bunch of different validators that can check CSS, web platforms (mobile ready), dead links, RSS, and one that checks all of these things.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>