<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COMP 426 on Modern Web Programming</title>
    <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content in COMP 426 on Modern Web Programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;span xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; xmlns:dct=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/terms/&#34;&gt;&lt;a property=&#34;dct:title&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34; href=&#34;https://comp426.johndmart.in&#34;&gt;COMP 426: Modern Web Programming&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; {year} by &lt;a rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL dct:creator&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; href=&#34;https://johndmart.in&#34;&gt;John D. Martin III&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/?ref=chooser-v1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;license noopener noreferrer&#34; style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;img style=&#34;height:13px!important;margin-left:3px;vertical-align:text-bottom;&#34; src=&#34;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/cc.svg?ref=chooser-v1&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;height:13px!important;margin-left:3px;vertical-align:text-bottom;&#34; src=&#34;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/by.svg?ref=chooser-v1&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;height:13px!important;margin-left:3px;vertical-align:text-bottom;&#34; src=&#34;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/nc.svg?ref=chooser-v1&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;height:13px!important;margin-left:3px;vertical-align:text-bottom;&#34; src=&#34;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/sa.svg?ref=chooser-v1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 04:15:05 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://comp426.johndmart.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>a00 This is all a setup</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/assignment/a00/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:52:13 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/assignment/a00/</guid>
        <description>The purpose of this is assignment is to get familiar with the tools that we will be using in COMP 426 for the rest of the semester as well as the assignment submission process.
Note that this first assignment, a00, is graded only for completion. Future assignments will be much deeper in scope, and you should expect to spend significantly more time on them.
Install Required Software Below are links to guides for installing the required software for this course.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>git</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/scm/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/scm/</guid>
        <description>git is a distributed version control system that keeps track of the changes between plaintext source files. It can be used for collaboration or for managing and keeping track of workflows for individuals. While primarily intended for software source code, git works with any plaintext files, and so can also be used for authoring of other kinds.
git basics git official documentation
You should become conversant with the official documentation for git.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GitHub</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hub/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:41:37 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hub/</guid>
        <description>GitHub is a platform that allows for users to keep copies of their open source, plaintext repositories online, in a single centralized location. It also adds a social interaction layer to the process of managing version-controlled source files.
GitHub Basics Hello World - GitHub Guides
Keeping GitHub forks up to date with upstream source Keeping your forked repo synced with the upstream source - Nitin Venkatesh
Syncing a fork - GitHub Help</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GitHub Actions</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hubactions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:42:12 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hubactions/</guid>
        <description>GitHub Actions allows for testing, compiling, and other workflow tasks to be performed on GitHub after you push to a repository housed there. COMP 426 uses these for autograding and other basic evaluation of assignments when you submit them. It is useful to become familiar with how it works so that you can monitor your autograded assignments when you submit them.
GitHub Actions - GitHub Docs</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GitHub Classroom</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hubclassroom/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:42:18 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/git/hubclassroom/</guid>
        <description>GitHub Classroom allows your instructors to distribute starter code for assignments, automatically create and manage repositories for student work, and automatically grade work sumbitted by push to GitHub. This is how all assignments will be managed for COMP426.
You can install an extension in VSCode that will let you simplify the process of accepting and submitting assignments.
Install GitHub Classroom extension on VSCode</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>a01 HTML and CSS</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/assignment/a01/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/assignment/a01/</guid>
        <description>In this assignment, we will create a set of HTML pages that are styled using CSS.
Follow the GitHub Classroom link for a01 listed on Piazza and Sakai. Clone the repository that it sets up for you. Just like last time, there will only be LICENSE AND README.md files in the repository when you clone it. You will create the rest of the files referenced below.
These pages should describe a mythological character or mythological story.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>mod01 HTML &#43; CSS Crash Course</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod01/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod01/</guid>
        <description>HTML and CSS The first real assignment is meant to get you comfortable with the basics of HTML and CSS. Whether you know it very well already or if you need a refresher, going through this module and then a01 should put you in a good position to continue through the rest of the assignments.
Knowing these markup languages is very important for being a good web developer. Both HTML and CSS are straightforward and well-documented.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>a02 CSS Frameworks</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/assignment/a02/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/assignment/a02/</guid>
        <description>Directly writing raw, static HTML and CSS is feasible for smaller sites like the mythical one you designed for a01. But it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see how designing a website from scratch can be difficult&amp;mdash;especially for large, complex, dynamic sites containing many pages.
And although every website you have ever used is ultimately expressed in terms of CSS and HTML, modern web developers typically have many tools at their disposal to help organize the code, reduce unnecessary duplication, and promote best practices.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>a03 JS Functions</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/assignment/a03/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/assignment/a03/</guid>
        <description>While writing HTML and CSS is necessary for making websites, the technolgy that does a lot of the behind-the-curtain work is JavaScript. It is the backbone of every modern web framework and is a necessity for makng interactive web pages.
This assignment, however, wont be using a web browser at all. When we want to execute JavaScript outside of the browser environment we use Node.js. This makes writing JavaScript like writing any other programming language.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>mod03 JavaScript Functions</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod03/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/module/mod03/</guid>
        <description>In a03, we&amp;rsquo;re writing some basic JS functions that can be called to return values outside of a web browser. This module includes some information and links about JS functions and a walkthrough of creating a very basic set. Some of this is covered in the a03 instructions as well. You can use this as a reference to expand on the information presented in the instructions.
How do functions work in JavaScript?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>a04 Build an API from scratch</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/assignment/a04/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/assignment/a04/</guid>
        <description>In this assignment, we will build, from scratch, an API that talks to a database of users. Eventually, we will use this method (and this exact database) to add authentication to a page that you previously createed in a01. This is all a lot easier than it seems at first.
There are a few basic concepts germane to this assignment that you will want to familiarize yourself with:
 REST (REpresentational State Transfer) CRUD (Create / Read / Update / Delete) SQL (Structured Query Language)  These concepts are explained in some detail in mod04, so you&amp;rsquo;ll want to have a look at that while we are working.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>JS Functions</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/javascript/functions/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/javascript/functions/</guid>
        <description>JavaScript Functions - w3schools
Functions - JavaScript - Mozilla Developer Network
Differences Between var and let - JavaScript Tutorials</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Node</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/javascript/node/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/javascript/node/</guid>
        <description>Node.js v16.10.0 documentation
ECMAScript Modules (ESM) ECMAScript Modules (ESM) documentation
Using ECMAScript modules (ESM) with Node.js - Diogo Souza</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Setup for Mac OSX</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/software/mac/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/software/mac/</guid>
        <description>To be a successful web developer in COMP 426, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install some software on your computer. Follow the guide on this page if you have a Mac running OSX.
Chrome Web Browser Your projects in this course will run in a web browser. While most web browsers should work, we only support and test in the Google Chrome web browser. Install it by following the instructions below. We suggest making it your computer&amp;rsquo;s default web browser.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Software setup for Windows</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/software/windows/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/software/windows/</guid>
        <description>To be a successful web developer in COMP 426, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install some software on your computer. Follow the guide on this page if you have a Windows computer.
Chrome Web Browser Your projects in this course will run in a web browser. While most web browsers should work, we only support and test in the Google Chrome web browser. Install it by following the instructions below. We suggest making it your computer&amp;rsquo;s default web browser.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Validators</title>
        <link>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/validators/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://comp426.johndmart.in/guide/validators/</guid>
        <description>Here are some links to validators that you can use to check your assignment code. We will run all your code through a validator as part of your assignment submission. You should too.
Validators will tell you exactly what you need to know to fix the errors in your code.
HTML, CSS, etc. W3C Markup Validation Service (HTML)
W3C has a bunch of different validators that can check CSS, web platforms (mobile ready), dead links, RSS, and one that checks all of these things.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>